Undeclared wars are commonplace.
Tragically, our government engages in
preemptive war, otherwise known as
aggression, with no complaints from the
American people. Sadly, we have become
accustomed to living with the
illegitimate use of force [music] by
government. To develop a truly free
society, the issue of initiating force
[music] must be understood
and rejected.
What if sometimes to love [music] your
country, you had to alter or abolish the
government? What if Jefferson was right?
What [music] if that government is best
which governs least?
What if it is dangerous to be right when
the government is wrong?
What if it is better to perish fighting
for freedom [music]
than to live as a slave?
What if freedom's greatest [music] hour
of danger
is now?
>> [music]
>> Hi everyone, Judge Andrew Napolitano
here for Judging Freedom. Today is
Monday, February 9th, 2026.
My long-time friend and former CIA
officer John Kiriakou joins us. Now,
John, always a pleasure. I was just
listening
to our intro, and some of it in the
voice of Ron Paul, some of it in my own,
and I mean this with the greatest of
respect and even affection. I guess you
are living proof that it is dangerous to
be right when the government is wrong.
I'm sorry to say that's been the case. I
was just talking to a friend of mine a
few minutes ago, and and she asked me if
I had applied for a presidential pardon.
And as you know, as you've helped me, I
have. And um
and I said, you know, it just pains me
that the process is so difficult because
the issues seem so clear in my mind.
Either there's a right or there's a
wrong and I I think that history has
vindicated me and
still just kind of waiting for my day.
Right. I think your day will come
my dear friend and I was privileged to
play a small role in that and obviously
I hope it is successful.
>> small. Thank you. Thank you. When when
US intelligence officers take an oath of
fidelity to the Constitution
um which includes things like due
process and no search and seizure
without a warrant. I mean, do they take
this oath seriously? Do they take it
literally? That's that's really the
question right there. I I say all the
time, I was one of about 300 people uh
on my first day at the CIA all sitting
in the CIA's auditorium called the
bubble and when I put my right hand in
the air and I swore to uphold the
Constitution and to protect it against
all enemies foreign and domestic, I hate
that I've had to come to the conclusion
that I was pretty much the only person
that day who actually meant it. Uh but
we should all be standing in support of
the Constitution. We should all want to
protect the Constitution and to uphold
the Constitution rather than whatever
policy happens to be in vogue or
whatever political party happens to
control the White House.
Of course I took the same oath. I took
that oath when I um
joined the military and then I took that
oath
when I was appointed uh to the bench.
But being a judge of course
have a a lot of leeway.
You're supposed to interpret the
Constitution as it was originally
understood but there are a variety of
means for interpreting it but when you
are
a CIA officer
I mean, do they tell you the president
will authorize you to break the law,
don't worry about it?
Yes, they do. And in fact, on the day
that I was asked if I wanted to be,
their words, trained in the use of
enhanced interrogation techniques, the
first words out of my mouth were, "That
sounds like a torture program and
torture is illegal."
And my colleague from the
Counterterrorism Center immediately
responded with, "It's not illegal, the
president approved it and the Justice
Department authorized it." And I said,
"I don't know what laws they're reading,
but this seems pretty obviously illegal
to me."
I was, I'm sorry to say, the only one of
14 people who who said no at the end of
the day. Do presidents
regularly authorize, maybe regularly is
the is the wrong word, I'll let you put
whatever adverb in there that you think
is a appropriate,
uh criminal behavior, kidnapping,
drug dealing, murder,
uh by
US intelligence agents?
I hate to say, but yes. Um in the most
egregious example, we have uh
what has become known as the Tuesday
morning kill list meeting, where during
the Obama administration, John Brennan
convened a group of
operations officers and attorneys from
the White House, the CIA and the Justice
Department to come up with a list of
people every Tuesday morning,
people who would be killed that week. Uh
once the names were agreed upon, the
teams would fan out around the world,
carry out their assassinations, and then
meet up again the following Tuesday for
for that week's list.
That's just murders.
Then you have to consider renditions or
extraordinary renditions, which are
different. A rendition is, if you are,
let's say, Tunisian and I capture you in
Afghanistan and I send you back to
Tunisia. That's a rendition.
If you're Tunisian and I catch you in
Afghanistan and I send you to Egypt and
I don't tell the Tunisian government,
but I know that in Egypt you're going to
be softened up a little bit, that's an
extraordinary rendition and that is just
simply not legal. And then when it comes
to to drugs, you know, it's taken us
decades to finally get the real story as
to what happened
uh uh with the Contra rebels and the
arrival of of cocaine in the United
States that ended up leading to the
crack uh epidemic.
Yeah, these all came out of White House
actions. And again, it doesn't matter
who's in the White House. It doesn't
matter what political party controls the
White House. This is not a partisan
issue. This is an issue where the
executive has overstepped and neither
Congress nor the courts have pushed
back.
Do uh agents ever worry that they might
be prosecuted by a subsequent uh
administration? I mean, suppose, just
throwing it out there, suppose Gavin
Newsom succeeds Donald Trump.
Uh might uh a Newsom Justice Department
uh prosecute those who caused the chaos
in Iran or participated in the uh
kidnapping of Nicolas Maduro?
Oh, certainly. Certainly. And that's why
the CIA um always insists on a
presidential finding or on an
interpretation of the law by the Justice
Department's Office of Legal Counsel
before they'll allow such an operation
to go forward. That that's come out of
the 1980s, actually, uh or the 1990s. I
had a friend at the agency, Robert Baer,
Bob Baer, who's made a name for himself
as a commentator.
He was serving in Iraq, uh northern Iraq
in the 1990s, and uh
uh he was working with uh with the Kurds
to see if he might be able to take out
Saddam Hussein, which he believed to be
his mission. This is what he had been
told to do. Well, one of his
communications was intercepted by NSA.
NSA informed the National Security
Advisor, Sandy Berger, that there was a
rogue CIA officer who was looking to
kill Saddam Hussein.
The NSC under Berger ordered the CIA to
bring Bob home,
and they threatened to charge him with
conspiracy to commit first-degree murder
in the, you know, murder of Saddam
Hussein. Uh he ended up having to leave
the agency. But in fact, Bob didn't do
anything wrong. Bob did exactly as he
had been told to do. And uh the
operation just fell apart, and the White
House was looking for a fall guy. That
happens with some frequency.
Do agents, groups of agents, management
and agents
go rogue, or do they always have the
knowledge and comfort of a presidential
authorization or or a DOJ authorization?
And before you answer, I got to tell you
what the courts have said
uh about DOJ legal opinions.
They're not worth the paper that they're
often not even printed on.
It That it's not a defense in a
courtroom that some lawyer in the
Justice Department told you you could do
it. Don't agents know that? No, they
don't. That's such an important point.
You know, I say all the time, Judge,
that we we have the 1946 Federal Torture
Act, which bans torture.
We have the United Nations Convention
Against Torture, which bans torture, and
which we wrote.
Right. But then,
you know, we we waterboard people, we
put them in freezing cells, and they end
up dying of hypothermia. We put them in
in enclosed spaces like coffins, and and
play Russian roulette with them, and
hold power drills to their heads, all in
violation of international law, and we
just pretend that it's okay. And I'll
add another thing. I say this all the
time, but I feel very strongly about it.
In 1946,
we executed Japanese soldiers who had
waterboarded American POWs. We executed
them. That was a death penalty crime.
In 1968, in January, the Washington Post
ran a front-page photograph of an
American soldier waterboarding a North
Vietnamese prisoner. That soldier was
prosecuted, and he was convicted and
sentenced to 20 years at Fort
Leavenworth.
The law never changed,
but by 2002, we just decided, "Oh, the
law doesn't apply to us. We're the good
guys. OLC says we can do this. We're
going to go do it." All right. OLC is
the Office of Legal Counsel in the DOJ
that reports to give legal advice to
other
aspects of the executive branch of the
government. These are the people that
the courts have said their words are not
a defense if you're a prosecutor, and
apparently
we know that that's not the case. When
um
the chaos was caused in the streets in
Iran, Mhm. and when we know from a
um
an ex-posting by former CIA director and
former secretary
of state Mike Pompeo that Mossad and CIA
agents were there. What kind of things,
what kind of behavior did the CIA do on
the ground in order to foment that
chaos,
which resulted in innocent people being
murdered in the streets?
>> Yes. Yes, it did. Well, we know, thanks
to Mike Pompeo's flapping gums,
that that this was a Mossad CIA
operation. It was always my experience
that the CIA just simply didn't have
people on the ground, but the Mossad
certainly certainly did, and and a lot
of people on the ground. But we now know
also that both the CIA and the Mossad
have cooperated very very closely with
the MEK, the Mujahedin-e Khalq.
The Mujahedin-e Khalq started off as
something akin to a cult. Uh it was
founded by a married couple couple, the
Rajavis. Uh the the husband mysteriously
disappeared in the 1970s. Um the rumor
was that his wife had had him killed and
just buried in the desert somewhere.
Maryam Rajavi took over the
organization. This is an organization
that tried to assassinate the US
ambassador in Iran in the 1970s, that
tried to assassinate an American
lieutenant general who was the highest
ranking military official in Iran, US
military official. And um and they were
given safe haven by Saddam Hussein in
northeastern Iraq. Well, in 2009, when
Hillary Clinton was the Secretary of
State, we decided to take the MEK off
the terrorism watch list. And
immediately the likes of everybody from
from
Rudy Giuliani to Howard Dean,
prominent people on the left and the
right in in everyday American politics,
they all started taking MEK money.
And they started lobbying for the MEK.
So all of a sudden now, Maryam Rajavi,
who was a murderous lunatic just prior
to this, was now feted in Washington at
these gigantic dinners,
spent millions of dollars hiring more
and more American political figures to
lobby
for the MEK. And then we have the Mossad
bragging that they have an operational
relationship with the MEK. One of the
things that surprised me with these
demonstrations, I I believed at the
outset that these were Mossad inspired
uh demonstrations. The Mossad actually
came out or the Israeli government came
out and said, "Yes, it was us. Aren't we
clever? Look how successful we were."
But what sort of tipped me off was that
these protesters were burning mosques,
for example. They burned 18,000 I'm
sorry, they burned 18 mosques. And then
they set fire to 38
fire trucks.
Well, if you're demonstrating for
democracy and freedom and, you know,
that kind of thing, why in the world
would you set mosques and and fire
engines on fire? That
that didn't make any sense to me. Well,
now it makes sense because
the Mossad and the CIA want chaos in
Iran. Chaos to try to bring down this
government. And listen, chaos has never
resulted in anything better, at least in
the near term.
If there is chaos, a whole lot of people
are going to die.
When uh President Trump said he didn't
know anything about the origins of the
chaos in the streets and he assumed that
they were spontaneous
demonstrations by uh shopkeepers and uh
consumers because the value of the
dollar
fell,
his uh Secretary of the Treasury, Scott
Bessent,
shockingly,
went on a national television and said,
"Yeah, we made the dollar we made the
the real, not the dollar. We made the
real uh fall. Uh we caused that to
happen. We know how to create uh
economic chaos and we did it to create
uh the problems in the streets."
Would that type of economic chaos
in the banking system in Iran, and would
that type of chaos, which included
murder
and arson,
as you've just described, John, in the
streets,
could that have happened without
presidential approval?
No.
No, that would be what is called a
covert action program.
And so that has to have very specific
presidential approval. It has to have
the president's signature after having
gone through the CIA General Counsel,
the Office of Legal Counsel at the
Justice Department, the National
Security Council General Counsel General
Counsel, and then the National Security
Advisor before it even gets to the
President. So, it has to be a very well
thought out plan that the President
finally approves with his signature
before it can be implemented. But, I'll
add that the Israelis often times just
can't control themselves. They can't
help themselves. They jump the gun
frequently before the US is ready to to
act alongside them.
And they'll just go in and start doing
something. One of the things that the
Israelis have been very very successful
at vis-a-vis Iran is that they recruited
hundreds, perhaps thousands, of Afghan
refugees. There are 2 million Afghan
refugees in Iran.
And
as refugees, they're entitled to no
government services at all. No food, no
water, no medical care, no housing, no
nothing. So, they're destitute.
Well, if the Israelis go in and say,
"Hey, we'll give you $200 a month if you
just stand on this street corner for 12
hours a day and look at that apartment
and tell me when the general comes out
of his out of his apartment onto his
balcony so that they can adjust their
missile GPSs to take out the general's
apartment."
They end up succeeding in that way. In
the US, we have a far heavier
bureaucracy. It takes longer for for
these plans to work their way through
the process.
If the Israelis want to do something,
they just do it.
Wow.
Um going to play a clip for you. It's um
uh Vice President Vance being
interviewed by my friend and former
colleague uh Megan Kelly
uh in which he's giving the
administration line as to why
uh Iran's nuclear enrichment needs to be
destroyed by violence.
And then the second part of the clip
uh, is about 12 years old and I think
you know the person being interviewed by
my friend, uh,
and former colleague at Fox, David
Asman,
about whether or not the Saudi, uh,
government has, uh, nuclear weapons. The
reason I raise this is because of your
familiarity with the person in the
Asman, uh, clip. Uh, and because of the
misleading nature of what, uh, the Vice
President, uh, is saying. Chris, can you
play that, please? What happens when the
same people who are shooting up a mall
or driving airplanes into buildings have
a nuclear weapon? That is unacceptable.
And it's not just them, because if the
Iranians get a nuclear weapon, you know
who gets a nuclear weapon like the next
day? The Saudi Arabians. People, uh, Mr.
Claridge have talked about Saudi Arabia.
They certainly have more money than
anybody in the Middle East. Are you
concerned about the possibility they may
get a nuclear bomb? Saudis already have
the bomb.
But people fail to remember
>> Let me hold on hold on a second, Mr.
Claridge. Let me just emphasize that
point, cuz that's that's an important
point. You say Saudi Arabia already has
a nuclear bomb? Oh, several. People
forget that it was the Saudis who
financed the Pakistani bomb.
They put billions of dollars into that
effort to create that that, uh, nuclear
capability. And in return, of course,
they got something.
Now, uh, people can argue whether it was
dibs on four nuclear devices or seven.
That's the argument. But no one who
really in the know argues that they do
have access to nuclear weapons.
First of all, do you know if the Saudis
have nuclear weapons? And secondly, did
did you know cuz he's no longer living
Mr. Clarridge and is he worthy of
belief?
Oh, Dewey Clarridge is a legendary
figure in CIA operations. He was a giant
from the 1980s. A giant who was
prosecuted actually for um his
involvement in the Iran-Contra affair.
Uh you know, one of the first things I
learned uh when I joined the CIA in
January of 1990 was that the Saudis had
long been seeking a nuclear bomb. Um I
also know that the that the Saudis are
more generous with Pakistan than with
any other country on the planet to the
point where
the city of Faisalabad, a city of some 7
or 8 million people in uh in
West Central, I'm sorry, in East Central
Pakistan was named after Saudi King
Faisal because of his generosity.
Uh the the Saudis
the Saudis
gave the gave the Pakistanis as much
money as they needed to to develop a
nuclear bomb as a counter to the
Indians. And I always assumed as Dewey
Clarridge did that
that the Pakistanis shared those nuclear
bombs with the Saudis. I believe that
was the quid pro quo. The question then
is do they have a delivery uh system? Do
they have a missile capable of carrying
a nuclear device? I think the answer is
probably no, but impossible to say. Um
listen, the bottom line for me is
whether you like Dewey Clarridge or not,
whether you like Dewey Clarridge's
politics or not, uh he was a serious
operator at the CIA. And if he says that
the Saudis have a nuclear bomb, I would
believe that the Saudis have a nuclear
bomb. Was he ever
in the importation
in his official capacity at the CIA of
cocaine into the United States?
I believe that he was.
Um you know, I've researched the
daylights out of this. Uh
there were two different Contra groups,
one in the north of Nicaragua and one in
the south. Um we were working with the
Contras in the north. The Contras in the
south were taking in Colombian cocaine.
And the CIA involvement at the very
least was to allow the cocaine through
the north of Nicaragua
unmolested, knowing that that cocaine
was making its way to the United States.
And in
in response to that
we would get no pushback from
the southern Contras to the arming of
the northern Contras and indeed the
southern Contras would continue to fight
against the Sandinistas. So, I I believe
it's been pretty well documented that
the that the CIA at the very least
allowed cocaine to come into the country
and at the at the worst um facilitated
cocaine coming into the country. So, uh
from time to time we have uh two people
on the show who say the opposite about
this. Uh Sheriff David Hathaway, who's
the sheriff of a county in Arizona but
spent 30 years with the Drug Enforcement
Administration including in senior
management positions, agrees with you
entirely.
Jack Devine, whom you may know or know
of, everybody smiles when I mention
Jack's name and who has become a friend
of mine, we're neighbors uh in New York
City, um
insists adamantly that that's not true,
that the CIA was never involved in
cocaine. Who's right and who's wrong?
I think the sheriff is right. I think
Jack Devine is wrong.
You know, I had the I had the good
fortune to work for Jack Devine briefly
in
oh, 2001
or 2002. Great guy, great officer, true
believer
in the CIA
and the belief that the CIA is the good
guy.
Um
God bless him.
I think he's either either willfully
wrong or just pretending that he you
know, like Sergeant Schultz used to say
on Hogan's Heroes, he knows nothing,
nothing. But I think the evidence is out
there that
that the CIA was facilitating the
importation of cocaine. Is the CIA
dangerous to American freedom?
Oh, I believe that it's it's
antithetical to American freedom. Only
because we've allowed it to be.
You know, there was this there was this
wonderful period from roughly 1975-76
until about 1982
where congressional oversight of CIA was
was real and it was hands-on. We're
talking about the Church Committee
becoming the Senate Select Committee on
Intelligence and the Pike Committee
becoming the House Permanent Select
Committee on Intelligence and they
really were hands-on overseers as we
needed.
By 1982 with the war in Nicaragua, the
gloves came off. Next thing you know,
we're arming them with
the help of the Iranians and Saudi
middleman and cocaine's coming into the
country and the the thing just went off
the rails. One of the things that I
learned at the CIA during my career
there is that they will push, push,
push, push until somebody pushes back.
And if nobody pushes back, well, they've
just reclaimed new territory or claimed
new territory and they're not giving it
up. And that's what we've seen over the
years where the committees now are
really little more than than
cheerleaders for the CIA rather than
being overseers and controllers of the
CIA. It's going to take another Church
and Pike Committee, period,
to rein the CIA in. And technology is so
advanced now, I'm not even sure that
that's possible. Wow, is this regulatory
capture? You know, where the regulated
entity ends up controlling its own
regulator, as often happens in the
banking industry. I think so. And if for
many, many years now,
all anybody at the CIA ever had to say
was, "9/11."
And everybody would just drop whatever
it is they were pushing back on. You
know, national security, 9/11.
Is the CIA involved in the Epstein case?
>> [sighs]
>> A couple of weeks ago I would have said
probably not, and now I say probably
yes.
We're seeing so much new information
from this 3 million document drop.
Uh we're seeing that the White House
counsel, uh Kathryn Ruemmler, for
example, uh who's now the general
counsel at Goldman Sachs, tried
repeatedly to connect Jeffrey Epstein
with John Brennan. We don't know if that
connection took place. I would guess
that it probably did, and certainly John
Brennan has never said anything about
it. But now in the last uh 48 hours,
we've learned that Epstein's lawyers
had specifically reached out to the CIA
to ask the CIA to confirm
its relationship with Jeffrey Epstein,
whatever that was. There's no indication
that the agency ever responded. There's
no indication that the National Security
Council responded, but Epstein was
actively seeking some sort of role with
the CIA. And it looks like he may have
had some sort of role with MI6 in the
UK, as well as with the Israelis that I
think many of us have speculated on over
the years.
Thank you, John. A great great
conversation. Your candor is so
refreshing. Of course, you you are
the next to the word candor in Webster's
unabridged should be a picture of John
Kiriakou. Thank you, my man. Thank you
so much, Your Honor. It's always such a
pleasure to see you. I just got a text
from Jack. Uh he wants your cell number.
I'm not going to give it to him. Um
>> [laughter]
>> I'm only kidding. I'm only kidding. I
wouldn't I will hear from him, I'm sure.
>> [laughter]
>> Thank you, John. All the best.
>> Pleasure's mine. Thank you.
What a great
great uh human being who of course went
to jail over the torture program, not
for torturing, of course. It's
antithetical to his morality,
but for revealing it.
Uh coming up, 2:00, Ian Proud from
London. How close is the British
government to collapsing over the
Epstein affair. And at 3:00 hour, a new
guest, an expert on military
expenditures, Ben Freeman. When is too
much money to the Pentagon going to lead
to more war?
Justin Paul Tarr for Judging Freedom.
>> [music]
[music]